Guide to the Melvin Wittler Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Subject File, 1826-2001; Series IV
  - Organizations and Conferences
    - Near East Christian Council: Includes consultation on unity, National Evangelical Church in Middle East, 1962 Jun-Nov (Box 16, Folder 196)
    - Orthodox Church: Symposiums on religion and environment, 1990 Sep- 1992 Jun (Box 16, Folder 197)
    - Penn. Northeast conference: Re. church and missionaries relationships, 1967 Nov- 1968 Jun (Box 16, Folder 198)
    - Penn. Northeast conference:, 1968 Aug- 1969 Apr (Box 16, Folder 199)
    - Turkish American University Association, 1989 Oct- 1992 Feb (Box 16, Folder 200)
    - Turkish Studies Association, no date (Box 16, Folder 201)
    - Union Church of Istanbul: Including minutes and reports, 1972- 1997 Oct (Box 17, Folder 202)
    - Union Church of Istanbul: Church bulletins, addresses, 1963-1995 (Box 17, Folder 203)
    - United Church of Christ, USA: Includes keynote addresses, information re. several churches, 1968 Jan, 1984 Nov (Box 17, Folder 204)
    - UPC/COEMAR: UCC/UCBWM joint staff conference, 1968 Jun (Box 17, Folder 205)
    - United Church Board for World Ministries (UCBWM): Includes reports and newsletters, 1962 May- 1968 Apr (Box 17, Folder 206)
    - UCBWM: Includes reports, 1969 Feb- 1984 Nov (Box 17, Folder 207)
    - UCBWM: Includes reports, 1985 Jun- 1990 May (Box 17, Folder 208)
    - Uniting General Council of the World Alliance of Reformed Churches, The International Council in Nairobi, 1970 Aug. (Box 17, Folder 209)
    - World Council of Churches: Includes reports on evangelism, religious discrimination, religious freedom, 1960 Jul- 1964 Nov (Box 17, Folder 210)
    - World Council of Churches: Includes consultation on religious freedom, 1965 Jan- 1965 Dec (Box 17, Folder 211)
    - World Council of Churches: Misc. subjects, 1966 Mar- 1986 Jun (Box 17, Folder 212)
    - World Council of Churches: Exec. council meetings Istanbul, 1987 May- 1995 May (Box 17, Folder 213)
    - World Council of Churches: Misc., 1988 Jun- 1995 May (Box 17, Folder 214)
  - Miscellaneous Topics
    - Arab-Israeli conflict, 1954 Apr.- 1967 Sep (Box 18, Folder 215)
    - Arab-Israeli conflict, 1967 Oct- 1995 Dec (Box 18, Folder 216)
    - Conflict resolution: Information regarding terrorism, 1980 Jan (Box 18, Folder 217)
    - Ecumenism: Includes various publications, 1968 Jun- 1996 Mar (Box 18, Folder 218)
    - Environmental issues, no date (Box 18, Folder 219)
    - Homosexuality: Includes deliberations of UCC regarding ordination, 1972-1984 (Box 18, Folder 220)
    - Missions: on being a missionary, 1956 Apr- 1974 Aug (Box 18, Folder 221)
    - Missions: Includes study course "So This is Missions", 1979 Aug (Box 18, Folder 222)
    - Numismatics: Regarding coins, seals, also re. minarets, 1959 Sep, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 223)
    - Physical anthropology, 1952-1953 (Box 18, Folder 224)
    - Prominent people: Includes tributes to Ataturk, Robert Kennedy, M.L. King Jr., 1968 (Box 18, Folder 225)
    - St. Nicholas Symposium, no date (Box 18, Folder 226)
    - Thanksgiving proclamations, 1863-1986 (Box 18, Folder 227)
    - Turkish collected items, no date (Box 18, Folder 228)
    - Turkish language documents, etc, no date (Box 18, Folder 229)
    - Turkish newspaper articles, no date (Box 18, Folder 230)
    - Vermont missionaries: India, 1826-1921 (Box 18, Folder 231)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1949-1996; Series V
  - Biographical documentation
    - Curriculum vitae, education, ordination, applications to mission board, 1952-1955, no date (Box 19, Folder 232)
    - Documents and records: Passport, health records, expense accounts, 1956-1977, no date (Box 19, Folder 233)
    - Pastoral activities: Conferences, speaking engagements, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 234)
    - Missionary relationships with churches, 1950-1994 (Box 19, Folder 235)
    - Pastoral activities: Notebook, 1950-1994 (Box 19, Folder 236)
    - Tributes and awards: Includes certificate of ordination, membership certificates, "Who's Who in America", 1952-1978 (Box 19, Folder 237)
    - Travel: Snapshots, trip to Scandinavia, postcards, 1976-1987, no date (Box 19, Folder 238)
    - News articles, 1956-1995 (Box 19, Folder 239)
    - Assistance to others: Regarding estates of 3 women, 1951-1988 (Box 20, Folder 240)
    - Assistance to others: Administration of Jinishian Memorial Program, 1979-1984 (Box 20, Folder 241)
    - Assistance to others: Administration of Jinishian Memorial Program, 1985-1987 (Box 20, Folder 242)
  - Children and Family
    - Nathan's records from Williston, 1972-1976 (Box 20, Folder 243)
    - Bryan's records for Robert College Comm. School, 1967-1974 (Box 20, Folder 244)
    - Kent at Williston, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 245)
    - Family letter, Valentine, death of MW's father, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 246)
  - Memorabilia
    - Programs, cards, invitations, etc., 1956-1996, no date (Box 20, Folder 247)
    - Sale of Byzantine Censer to Metropolitan Museum of Art, NY, 1976-1985 (Box 20, Folder 248)
    - State dinner with Turkish President and M/M. George Bush, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 249)
    - Collection of ideas and quotes, 1980-1981, no date (Box 20, Folder 250)
    - Miscellaneous material: addresses, clippings, 1949-1986 (Box 20, Folder 251)
    - Photographs of Nancy and Melvin Wittler, Near East Christian Council Triennial 1967, church leaders in the Near East, 1967, 1990, no date (Box 20, Folder 252)